Aniraj Kesavan

+1-801-425-7410

anirajkesavan@gmail.com

Career Objective

To build a career in software development in core research and development areas, preferably dealing with very large scale distributed systems and storage services. Key skills involve strong fundamentals in data structures and operating systems and keen interest in engaging people for learning - mentoring process.

Work Experience

R&D Engineer - Pipeline, DreamWorks Animation India (May 2012 - Present)

- Worked on the development of infrastructure pipeline for the Animation Studio.
- Developed and maintained a workflow execution engine based on flow based programming and graph
- Credited as R&D Engineer for the 3 Hollywood productions
 - **How To Train Your Dragon 2** 0
 - **Penguins Of Madagascar** 0
 - Home

Associate Software Engineer, Zynga India (May 2012 – November 2012)

- Worked in Storage Services team in the R&D arm of the company, ZCloud Engineering.
- Predominantly involved in the development and maintanence of company's storage stack
- Involved in enhancing the capabilities of a the open source project, Zbase.
- Part of fast paced development cycles and the team that fully owns the product.
- Added operational experience in version control systems and UNIX.
- Predominantly worked on PHP with limited exposure in scripting via shell/python.

Software Engineering Intern, Zynga India Duration: 3 Months (May 2011- July 2011)

- Served as a summer intern at Systems Engineering Group, Zynga Inc.
- Involved in development of an automation framework for membase, a famous NOSQL Database.
- Languages used: PHP, HTML, Shell.

Academic Background

COURSE	INSTITUTION-UNIVERSITY	YEAR	AGGREGATE
D. Tarak	0		
B.Tech (Computer Science and Engineering)	Govt. Model Engineering College. Cochin University of Science and Technology	2012	65.26%
Class XII	Technical Higher Secondary School, Vattamkulam. Kerala State Board (Technical)	2008	91.09%
Class X	Technical Higher Secondary School, Vattamkulam. Kerala State Board (Technical)	2006	89.60%
Academic Projects	, ,		

SSL Support for Python (v3+): 8th Semester Main Project

- Team size: 4 Duration: 6 Months
- An attempt to provide native SSL support for python by implementing the various algorithms and integrating OpenSSL functionalities as a library package in python modifying standard socket module of python 3.3.
- Implementation of various cryptographic algorithms and a selection algorithm to choose the best from available algorithms.
- Modifying socket module so as to implement a TLS secure interface underlying the application protocol.
- Platform: Python v3.3
- Tools used: Eclipse IDE pydev platform.
- Languages: Python, C.

DRONA: Army Firing Training Manager: 6th Semester Mini Project for *Indian Armed Forces*. Team-size: 4 Duration: 4 Months

- Co-ordinates all activities in the Firing training program from ammunition allotment, candidate selection to database management and analyses the result to produce graphical analysis report.
- Interacted with military personnel for feasibility and requirement updates.
- Platform: Google Android 1.6(Donut).
- Tools: SQLite v3, Eclipse IDE, Android SDK r08, Open GL ES 1.0.
- Languages: JAVA, XML.

Awards and Achievements

- Winner of Daily Quiz at IBM The Great Minds Challenge Season 2, 2011.
- Secured First prize in Dispatch 'em, Team coding event at Conjura 2012, T K M College of Engineering, Kollam.
- Secured First Prize in Decrypt, C Coding competition at Aavishkaar 09, College of Engineering Trivandrum.
- Secured First Prize in Code of Wars, Coding competition at TechKshethra 2011, Rajagiri School of Engineering Technology.
- Secured Third Prize in Lord Of the Code, C Coding competition at Excel 2010, Model Engineering College.
- Secured First Place in Blue, Bluetooth based treasure held as a part of Explendor 2010, CUSAT.
- State level Finalist in IT Quiz conducted by ITES.

Positions of Responsibility

- Student Coordinator, Placement Cell- Harmonises with a team of another 13 members in the activities of Placement Cell, the student body that deals with the corporate relationships of the college.
- Core member of MACS (MEC Association for Computer Students) .
- Active member of **Illuminati**, the Quiz club of Model Engineering College.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Participated and won various prizes for Dumb Charades and literary events during college and school.
- Actively participated for Drama and Mime in College and school.

References (Consent of candidate required before contacting, contact details will be provided)

- Mr. Murali Mohanan, Asst. Professor & HOD, Computer Science and Engineering, Govt. Model Engineering College. Thrikkakara.
- Shan Kadavil, Country Manager, Zynga Game Network India Pvt Ltd.
- Satheesh Subramanian, R&D Manager, DreamWorks Animation India